Finding Aid for Louis D. Belcher papers, 1968 and 1976-1985
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Topical File
  - Chamber of Commerce 1979-1984, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - China (Taiwan) 1980 (Box 13)
  - Citizen Surveys 1977-1978 (Box 13)
  - City-University Coordinating Committee (Box 13)
    (see University of Michigan)
  - Civic Theatre 1978-1984 (Box 13)
  - Cleary College 1981-1984 (Box 13)
  - Community Action on Substance Abuse (CASA) (Box 13)
    (see Marijuana Ordinance Ballot Issue)
  - Concord Conference (Box 13)
    (see GOP)
  - Conference and Visitors' Bureau 1982-1984 (Box 13)
  - Conference Center 1978, 1984 (Box 13)
  - COPE (Center for Occupational and Personalized Education, Inc.) 1979-1984 (Box 13)
    (see also Community Development in City Government series)
  - Corrections Review Committees 1981-1982 (Box 13)
  - Council for Retirement Industry 1982 (Box 13)
  - Cultural Affairs Department Proposal 1980 (Box 13)
  - C, Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Danish News Bookshop 1980, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Da Vinci Art Exhibit 1982 (Box 13)
  - Day Care Centers 1984 (Box 13)
  - Detroit Edison 1981, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Downtown Club 1978-1984 (scattered) (Box 13)
  - D, Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Ecology Center 1978-1984 (Box 13)
  - Economic Growth Steering Committee 1981-1983, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - EMU (Eastern Michigan University) Exchange File 1978-1982 (Box 13)
  - Enterprise Zones 1981-1983 (Box 13)
  - E, Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Family Group Homes 1978-1979 (Box 13)
  - Flooding (see Utilities Department in City Government series) (Box 13)
  - F, Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Garden Homes 1975-1976 (Box 13)
  - General Services Administration 1980-1981 (Box 13)
  - GOP (including Concord Conferences)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 13)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 13)
    - 1982-1985 (Box 13)
  - Great Lakes Environmental Research Laboratory 1983-1984 (Box 13)
  - G, Miscellaneous (Box 13)
  - Halfway House, Proposal for 1981-1982 (Box 13)
    (see also Kambly Property in Planning File)
  - Hands-on Museum 1978-1983, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Hazardous Waste 1982 (Box 14)
  - Herman Miller Research Corp. 1978-1979 (Box 14)
  - Hikone (Box 14)
    (see H, Miscellaneous; also see Correspondence in Personal series)
  - H, Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - I, Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Jobs Partnership Training Act (JPTA) 1983-1984 (Box 14)
  - John Knox Senior Citizen Village 1977-1979 (Box 14)
  - Leslie Laboratories 1982-1984 (Box 14)
  - Lousma Day 1982 (Box 14)
  - L, Miscellaneous (Box 14)
  - Marijuana ordinance Ballot Issue 1982 (Box 14)
  - Mayors' Exchange Days
    - Oak Park 1978 (Box 14)
    - Port Huron 1979 (Box 14)
    - Trenton 1980 (Box 14)
    - Marquette 1981 (Box 14)
    - Fenton 1982 (Box 14)
    - Farmington Hills 1983 (Box 14)
    - East Detroit 1984 (Box 14)
  - Metropolitan Fund/Metropolitan Affairs Corp. 1981 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Consolidated Gas Company 1981-1985 (scattered) (Box 14)
  - Michigan Ensemble Theatre 1981-1984 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Rowing Association 1984 (Box 14)
    (see also Barton Ponds in Planning File series)
  - Michigan, State of
    - General 1980-1984 (Box 14)
    - Miscellaneous Departments 1975-1984 (Box 14)
    - State Housing Development Authority 1981-1984 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Technology Council 1981-1983 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Theatre
    - General
      - 1979-1980 (Box 14)
      - 1981-1984 (Box 14)
    - Finances, Solicitations, and Contributors 1981-1984 (Box 14)
    - Millionaires' Parties 1982-1984 (Box 15)
    - Purchase and Lease Agreements 1979-1982 (Box 15)
  - Multi-Ethnic Festival/Multi-Ethnic Alliance 1981-1984 (Box 15)
  - M, Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Nazi Rallies 1982-1984 (Box 15)
  - North Central Property Owners Association, Inc. 1979-1981 (Box 15)
  - N, Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Old Westside Neighborhood Group 1975-1977 (Box 15)
  - Open Meetings Lawsuit 1978 (Box 15)
  - O, Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Peace Neighborhood Center 1980-1984 (Box 15)
  - People to People 1969-1983 (includes newsletters) (Box 15)
  - Pigeon Control 1981-1983 (Box 15)
  - Pittsfield Township 1978-1982 (Box 15)
  - Pornography (Box 15)
    (see Danish News Bookshop)
  - Post Office 1978-1979 (Box 15)
  - Pre Employment Training and Career Development Consulting Firm 1981-1983 (Box 15)
  - Private Industry Council (Box 15)
    (see Jobs Partnership Training Act)
  - Project Grow 1978-1982 (Box 15)
  - Purcell, Carl D. (Box 15)
    (see U.S. Government, Congress)
  - P, Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Reapportionment 1981 (Box 15)
    (see also City Clerk in City Government series)
  - Recycle Ann Arbor 1979-1982 (Box 15)
  - Retired Senior Volunteer Program 1978-1984 (includes newsletters) (Box 15)
  - R, Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Safety Town 1979-1984 (Box 15)
  - Schools (Box 15)
    (see Ann Arbor Public Schools)
  - Scio Township 1978-1984 (Box 15)
  - Security Rental Units 1983 (Box 15)
  - Senior Citizens Guild 1984 (Box 15)
  - Senior Housing Co-op 1978 (Box 15)
  - Sister Cities (Box 15)
    (see H, Miscellaneous; T, Miscellaneous; People to People; Blacktown, Australia; see also Correspondence in Personal series)
  - Sister Lakes Drain 1979-1981 (Box 15)
  - Soccer, U.S. Federation 1983 (Box 15)
  - State Street Merchants' Association 1978-1982 (Box 15)
  - South State Street Improvements 1981-1983 (Box 15)
  - Summer Festival (Box 15)
    (see Ann Arbor Summer Festival)
  - S, Miscellaneous (Box 15)
  - Taiwan (Box 15)
    (see China)
  - Taxes
    - General 1978-1980 (Box 15)
    - Abatements 1978-1984 (Box 15)
    - Letters from Constituents 1981 (Box 15)
  - Tibet (Visit by the XVI Gyalwa Karmapa) 1980 (Box 15)
  - Tubigen (Box 15)
    (see T, Miscellaneous; see also Correspondence in Personal series)
  - T, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Unions (AFSSCE Local 369 and Police Command Union) 1978-1982 (Box 16)
  - U.S. Government
    - Congress 1980-1982 (Box 16)
    - Department of Commerce 1978-1983 (Box 16)
    - Department of Housing and Urban Development 1977-1984 (Box 16)
      (see also Arrowwood Hills in Topical File; Community Development in City Government series)
    - Department of the Interior 1978-1982 (Box 16)
    - Department of Labor 1982-1984 (Box 16)
      (see also JTPA in Topical File; CETA in City Government series)
    - Department of Transportation 1976-1980 (Box 16)
    - White House Staff 1981-1984 (Box 16)
  - University of Michigan 1978-1984 (Box 16)
  - Urban Area Transportation Study Committee (UATS), Ann Arbor-Ypsilanti 1980-1982 (Box 16)
  - Urban-Suburban Affairs 1978-1980 (Box 16)
  - U, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Veterans' Administration Medical Center 1979-1984 (Box 16)
  - Veterans Park 1978-1981 (Box 16)
  - Veterans Awareness Week 1979 (Box 16)
  - Ward Data 1982 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw Contractors Association 1980-1983 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw Council for the Arts 1979-1982 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw County Administrator 1981-1983 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw County Coordinating Council for Children at Risk 1984 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw County Council on Alcoholism (Box 16)
    (see Alcoholism)
  - Washtenaw County Economic Development 1982 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw County Economic Development Partnership 1982 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw County Parks 1980 (Box 16)
  - Washtenaw Development Council 1982-1984, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Water Quality Management Plan 1978-1983 (Box 16)
  - W & Y, Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Ypsilanti 1979-1983 (Box 16)
    (see also Washtenaw Development Council)
- Photographs
  Most of the photograph folder listings are self-explanatory. The Personal photos include portraits, pictures of the mayor at ceremonial functions, giving addresses, or meeting with constituent groups, and a few "candid" shots. The Miscellaneous folder contains contact negatives and negatives of Belcher with representatives of the Jewish community and unidentified persons (probably members of the mayor's office staff).
  - Personal (Box 16)
  - Planning-Kleinschmidt P.U.D. (Box 16)
  - Topical File
    - Blacktown, Australia (Box 16)
    - GOP-Concord Conference (Box 16)
    - Mayors' Exchange Days
      - Oak Park 1978 (Box 16)
      - Farmington Hills 1983 (Box 16)
    - Tibet (Box 16)
    - Veterans' Administration Medical Center-Salute to Hospitalized Veterans February 1981 (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 16)
  - Photo of Belcher with President Reagan (Folder 1)